# SPENCER RINEHART

Austin, TX (757) 630-3572

# anubis@overthemonkey.com

I am a full-stack engineer with over fifteen years of PHP experience and over six years of Node.js experience. I have extensive experience using Linux as a development environment and the base of a production software stack. Over my career, I have built the DevOps foundation at multiple companies using Docker, Ansible, Jenkins CI, and Amazon Web Services. I am passionate about establishing best practices for an engineering team and improving the tooling for developing and delivering software.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### TWYLA

Lead Software Engineer April 2018-Present

Software Engineer July 2017-April 2018

I am currently a lead software engineer at Twyla where we are developing a custom e-commerce platform for selling high quality, limited-edition art prints. I developed the Node.js backend to a GraphQL-based application using React on the frontend. I lead a small, agile team of engineers and work on the executive team to help set the company-wide product strategy and timeline.

#### **FLOSPORTS**

Software Engineer January 2016–June 2017

At FloSports, I was a software engineer working on their live-streaming platform for sporting events. I used my experience with PHP to quickly build a centralized identity API for managing athletes and teams. Using that framework, I also helped build an event registration system for athletes and teams using Angular 2. I also built the API platform for the next-generation live-streaming platform using the Serverless framework on AWS Lambda.

### HELP.COM

Software Engineer September 2014–January 2016

I was a full-stack software engineer for Help.com where I helped build a live chat application. I laid the foundation for a Docker-based production deployment system and built some of the core components of Help.com's microservice-based architecture. I worked extensively on building Node.js microservices and instrumenting them in our frontend Ampersand.js (a Backbone.js derivative) application.

### DOMINION ENTERPRISES-TRADERONLINE.COM

Web Programmer June 2006-September 2014

I worked at Dominion Enterprises for 8 years on a variety of web applications, APIs, and DevOps/Systems applications. My primary role was a PHP software engineer with a focus on APIs and core functionality. I also led projects for release management and server/process automation. I was the head of a company-wide Open Source committee and a member of the company's Technical Talent Acquisition Group (TTAG).

Some of the key projects that I led include:

- introducing and managing version control systems, unit testing, and automated release processes;
- $\bullet \ \ \mbox{developing RESTful APIs and converting applications to access it;}$
- developing an AWS-based automated deployment process utilizing continuous delivery; and
- establishing the company's open source portfolio, leading up a committee to maintain it, and evangelising OSS to the company as a whole.

The websites I serviced are primarily focused on classified advertising and dealer inventory and recieve thousands of requests per minute. I gained at-scale experience with PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS/Less, Puppet, Chef, Linux, and MongoDB, among other technologies.

# **#** EDUCATION

# VIRGINIA TECH

Computer Science August 2003-May 2006

In three years, I received a B.S. in Computer Science.

# **S**KILLS

# PRIMARY EXPERTISE

- PHP 15+ years
- Node.js 6+ years
- Docker 5+ years
- Linux 15+ years

# ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- HTML/CSS/JS 15+ years
- AWS 5+ years
- React 1 year
- Ansible/Chef 3+ years